JOHN : Hang on . I know .
KATE : Mm .
You 're doing so good .
JOHN : You 're doing so good . You all right ?
- Yeah . - Okay .
WOMAN [ OVER PA ] : Dr. Matthews to the nurses ' station .
JOHN : Excuse me .
My wife 's in labor . We called ahead for Dr. Wheeler .
MAN : I just need you to fill this out , please .
- Thank you . - Have a seat , hon .
[ GROANING ]
- I 'll be right up . KATE : Yeah .
- Okay ? - Okay .
- Is this your first ? - No , no , it 's our third .
MAN : Sir , can you sign here ?
We 're gonna name her Jessica .
[ GROANING ]
WOMAN : Vitals look good .
KATE : Where 's John ?
- Where 's my husband ? MAN : Just relax now .
Everything 's gonna be okay .
What 's happening ? What are you doing ?
I 'm so sorry for your loss .
- What ? - Your baby 's dead .
No , it 's not dead . It 's alive .
What are you talking about ? It 's moving .
It 's a terrible loss . We 're so sorry .
- Just relax . - No !
What ? No , no , no . Put me to sleep . I wanna be asleep .
MAN : It 's too late for that . - No !
It 's okay , you 're doing great .
What are you doing ? What are you doing ?
MAN : You might feel some tugging .
[ SCREAMING ]
Oh , my God . This isn 't happening .
[ BABY CRYING ]
Congratulations , Mrs. Coleman . It 's a girl .
[ SCREAMING ]
WOMAN : Yes , Kate , your dreams can be a manifestation of your emotions .
It 's your body and mind 's way of dealing
with the stress and grief of what happened .
What if this has nothing to do with the stillbirth ?
What do you think it 's about ?
We 're seeing kids for the first time this weekend .
And maybe the nightmares ... .
Maybe I 'm just not ready to adopt yet .
I drove by the wine shop on the way home the other night .
Did you stop ?
No . Wanted to . The thought went through my brain , you know ?
It wasn 't for myself . It wasn 't ... .
I just thought it would be nice to have a bottle handy , in case we had guests .
But you didn 't go in .
Mm-mm .
The key , to me
is not that you had the urge
but that you resisted it .
You wouldn 't have made it through the home study if you weren 't ready .
But , ultimately
you have to decide .
Hi .
Honey , hello .
Let me see . Ooh . Did you paint this ?
[ SIGNING ]
It 's a beautiful butterfly . It 's fantastic .
Really wonderful . Good .
Let 's go . I 'm cold .
[ CAR HORN HONKING ]
[ TRUCK HORN HONKING ]
Are you okay ?
[ THUDS ]
[ HUMMING ]
[ THUDDING ]
Ah !
Max !
Stop throwing !
I 'm working .
KATE : No , honey , I 'm sorry .
Just take a break for a little while , okay ?
Because Mommy 's trying to play . Okay ?
Daddy 's here .
- Mine . - Hey .
- Hi . JOHN : Sorry , practice went a little late .
KATE : It 's all right . DANIEL : Whoa .
JOHN : Okay , tough guy . Give me that . DANIEL : Wicked .
No , no .
JOHN : Shoot it , shoot it . Go , go , go , go .
DANIEL : No . JOHN : Yes ! Give me five .
Hey , how did it go ? Daniel .
Fine .
JOHN : Hey .
Okay .
DANIEL : Five minutes . I 'm at the last level .
JOHN : No more video games . Brush your teeth .
DANIEL : That 's no fair . It won 't save . Come on , Dad , please ?
[ HEARING AID BEEPS ]
[ MUTED SOUND ]
[ SIGNING ]
[ GASPS ]
Sorry .
Sorry , sorry , sorry .
God .
[ INHALES DEEPLY ]
You smell good .
Okay .
All right .
I have to stop being like this .
JOHN : I get it .
I 'm very excited , I 'm happy .
I get nervous .
I 'm really scared .
Last time I felt all of this was right before I lost the baby .
I don 't want you to feel like we have to go through with this for my sake .
It 's not just- - It 's not for you .
I wanna take the love we felt for Jessica
and I wanna give it to somebody who really needs it .
Are you sure , hon ?
Yes .
GIRL 1 : Wanna make a snowman ? GIRL 2 : Sure .
GIRL 3 : It 's really cold out here .
GIRL 4 : Hey , stop it .
[ GIRL 5 GASPS ]
WOMAN : Hi . KATE : Hi .
So glad you could make it .
- So are we . - Yeah , finally , right ?
- So good to see you . ABIGAIL : Thank you for coming .
- This is really something . ABIGAIL : So go take a look around .
- Stay out of trouble . JOHN : Yeah , yeah .
Look at the snow orphan .
KATE : Snow orphan ?
Uh , snorphan ?
[ CHATTERING AND LAUGHING ]
GIRL : Hey . WOMAN : No , show it to Sister Mary .
[ GIRL SINGING " GLORY OF LOVE " ]
[ GIRLS LAUGHING ]
WOMAN : Slow down , slow down . GIRL 1 : You can 't catch me .
GIRL 2 : Yes , I can .
ESTHER : Hello ?
Hi .
[ ESTHER SINGING " GLORY OF LOVE " ]
Are all these paintings yours ?
- Yes . Do you like them ? - They 're remarkable .
Thank you .
My name is Esther . What 's yours ?
John . Nice to meet you .
- Can I take a seat ? - Of course .
I never get tired of watching these kids enjoy the party .
It really is . I 'm so sorry we didn 't do this sooner .
Don 't be . It 's a big leap .
Adopting an older child is not an easy decision to make .
KATE : John 's in the bathroom .
ABIGAIL : Think he 'll find us ? Do you wanna go look for him ?
- Where did you get the idea for this one ? - My paintings always tell stories .
This one 's about a sad mother lion who can 't find her cubs .
- She 's smiling . - She 's dreaming about her babies .
It 's the only thing that makes her happy .
- I hope she finds them . - She will . Look .
They were lost in the jungle , and they were so scared
because they didn 't have a mother .
Just when they thought they 'd be alone forever
they found their mother asleep under this tree .
Now when she wakes up , her dream will have come true .
- She 'll have her family again . - Amazing . You came up with that story ?
KATE : I think I hear his voice down here . - Yes .
Hey . I want to introduce you . This is my wife , Kate .
Kate , this is Esther .
Hello .
How are you ? Nice to meet you .
She painted all these .
- Really ? - Yeah .
These are fantastic . These are really wonderful .
- Thank you . - Where did you learn how to do this ?
I 've just had lots of time to practice , I guess .
It 's really boring here .
It 's boring here ?
If you 're so bored , why aren 't you down at the party ?
I 've never really seen the point of it . Nobody 's ever talked to me before .
I guess I 'm different .
There 's nothing wrong with being different .
JOHN : Well , you two have a lot in common .
[ LAUGHING ]
ESTHER : I think people should always
try to take the bad things that happen to them
and turn them into something good .
- Don 't you ? - Yeah .
Absolutely .
ABIGAIL : She 's originally from Russia , but it 's amazing how strong her English is .
She 's only been in the country a few years .
You get children from other countries ?
It 's rare . But when we do , it 's sometimes difficult to place them .
The family that brought her to America died in a house fire .
In a fire ?
My God .
Esther barely got out .
She 's been through a lot , but this is an extraordinary little girl .
She 's very bright . She 's very mature for her age .
And she 's very well-mannered . She 's a bit of a princess , actually .
She wears those ribbons on her wrists and her neck all the time .
Mine too .
We had trouble with her when we tried to take them off .
How does she get along with other kids ?
Oh , when she has to interact , she 's great .
Babe ?
- She really did seem to open up with us . - Yeah .
ABIGAIL : I thought she more than opened up with you .
You seem to have made quite a connection .
I could get the paperwork together and see you back here in three weeks .
All right .
Okey-dokey .
ABIGAIL : Call me if you need anything .
Bye . Okay , thank you .
Oh , that 's T-H .
T-H . Yeah .
And " Max " is like this ?
KATE : Yeah .
Good .
- Is this your house ? JOHN : Now it 's your house too .
KATE : Hi , sweetie . Hi . Look who 's here .
Hello , Max . My name is Esther .
She 's been practicing the whole way .
- Can she hear ? KATE : A little .
She was born almost completely deaf .
That just allows her to hear enough to read lips .
JOHN : That 's all right , I got it .
[ DOOR OPENS ]
JOHN : I 'd like to introduce you to Grandma Barbara .
It 's a pleasure to meet you .
That 's precious . It 's a pleasure to meet you too .
Danny .
This is Esther .
Hello , Daniel .
Hey .
[ WHISPERS ] Why does she dress like that ?
- Come on . Stop it . - I 'm just asking a question .
Oh !
- You have a piano ? - Yeah .
- Would you like to learn how to play ? - I would love to .
Do you like it ?
- It 's perfect . KATE : Good .
Thank you .
How do you say " thank you " ?
[ SIGNING ]
[ ROCK MUSIC PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS ]
JOHN : Wow , look at that .
What ? What ? What ?
DANIEL : Dad , look .
- Dad . JOHN : Where did you get that ?
DANIEL : Dad , look , I 'm killing Trevor . JOHN : Great .
Yes .
[ GASPS ]
ESTHER : Thank you .
Come on , Dad . My solo 's gonna end . Hurry , look .
Wow , cool .
DANIEL : Trevor , you suck . TREVOR : Shut up .
KATE : That 's fabulous .
Come on , guys . This is lame .
I was just about to beat you .
I 'm glad you like it , honey .
Come on , guys .
TREVOR : Hurry up , I 'm freezing my ass off .
DANIEL : Dude , it 's all in here . BOY : Oh , God . My hands are freezing .
DANIEL : Oh , man , she 's hot .
- Move over , man . - Page 34 will change your life .
Whoa .
This looks like your mom .
[ LAUGHING ]
No .
Esther and Maxine seem to be getting along well .
Yeah .
BARBARA : How 's she doing , Kate ?
Esther 's fitting right in .
I meant Maxine .
She 's playing by the pond like nothing ever happened .
She doesn 't remember , does she ?
No . She 's fine .
So , what are your plans ?
KATE : You know , probably get Esther settled
then go back to teaching .
Thought they weren 't gonna take you back .
No , I 'm not talking about Yale .
I 'll just- - I 'll probably give lessons from home .
That 's too bad . That was a very good job .
Well , I didn 't quit because I wanted to .
I know . You had to have your moment of clarity .
That is an A.A. term .
And I didn 't go to A.A. I just stopped drinking .
Same difference . We all need a wake-up call sometimes .
[ MOANING ]
Hi .
KATE : Hi . - Come here .
[ KNOCKING ]
KATE : Yeah ?
- Oh , hey . - We 're scared of the lightning .
Oh , come in .
- I wanna sleep next to Daddy . - Hang on .
Okay .
JOHN : I 'm gonna call later , make sure everything 's okay .
Okay . They 're gonna love your design .
- You gonna pick up the phone ? - Yeah .
All right .
KATE : Esther ?
Esther ?
Come on .
Esther , come on , we gotta go !
You gotta be kidding me .
KATE : Wow . Uh ... .
- Will you please go wait in the car ? - Come on .
Sweetheart , this isn 't really a school dress .
But I like it . Don 't you think it 's pretty ?
Yes , it 's so beautiful
but I just don 't think you 're gonna be comfortable in it .
What about those jeans ?
You 're afraid the other children will laugh at me .
I thought you said there wasn 't anything wrong with being different .
Yes , you 're right . You 're absolutely right .
Okay . Have fun .
Take a seat , please . Take a seat .
Don 't make me ask again , please .
Okay , this is our new student . Her name 's Esther Coleman .
And I 'd like you all to make her feel very welcome today .
Oh , look . Little Bo Peep texted me . She wants her outfit back .
[ LAUGHING ]
TEACHER : Okay , go take a seat .
Okay , if everybody could turn to Page 27 ... .
KATE : No !
No ! Esther , what are you doing ?
Get away from there ! No !
You don 't play near the water ! You know that !
Come on , get out !
ESTHER : Max .
[ PAINTBALL GUN SHOOTING ]
Sweet . Bull 's-eye .
Got you .
ESTHER : Did you kill it ? - I didn 't think it would hurt him .
Put it out of its misery .
- It 's in pain , and it 's your responsibility . - It was just an accident .
If you walk away now , it 'll starve to death .
Is that what you want ?
I 'm not doing it .
It 's all right .
- It 's in heaven now . - What 's wrong with you ?
KATE : Is the water warm enough ? ESTHER : Yes , thank you .
KATE : Okay . Call me if you need anything .
Esther ?
Esther .
Open this door .
- What are you doing ? - I always lock the door .
No , we don 't lock doors in this house .
But what if someone comes in and sees me ?
Nobody 's gonna come in .
Look , I 'm gonna stand right here , if that 's what you want .
ESTHER : I could sing for you .
I used to sing for the sisters so they would know I was all right .
Okay .
All right . But you know what ? This is just for tonight .
[ ESTHER SINGING " GLORY OF LOVE " ]
[ BELL RINGS ]
Your parents must have gone to a lot of retard camps to find her .
Watch it .
[ KIDS LAUGHING ]
GIRL : Are you okay ?
Is this a Bible ?
Jesus Freak brought a Bible to school today .
GIRL 1 : Hey , wanna come over ?
GIRL 2 : Good one . - Your sister 's a total spaz .
She 's not my sister .
GIRL 2 : I can 't believe you did that .
Oh , little doggy . Is this your collar , little doggy ?
[ SCREAMING ]
Not A. A , B.
You did really good .
No , I didn 't . I made like 11 mistakes .
I 'll do better next time .
Your teacher told me what happened today .
Don 't you want to talk about it ?
There 's nothing to talk about .
You know I 'm here for you , right ? You know that , right ?
I got something I wanna show you .
I have one just like this that I use as a diary .
And I thought that maybe you and I could use this one
for a scrapbook .
That 's Mommy and Daddy on their wedding day .
That 's Daniel , Christmas morning .
Here 's Max .
And there 's you .
Who 's Jessica ?
Max talks about her .
KATE : " I never held you , but I feel you .
You never spoke , but I hear you .
I never knew you , but I love you . "
What happened to her ?
She died while she was still in my tummy .
But we scattered her ashes here .
And as long as this plant grows
then part of her will be alive inside it .
She would have been lucky .
You 're a great mommy .
Thank you , sweetheart .
Thank you . It means a lot .
JOHN : How are you ? KATE : I 'm good .
It 's very interesting . Esther started to open up today .
JOHN : That 's very interesting .
KATE : I 'm starting to feel like there 's a real connection .
Me too .
[ LAUGHING ]
KATE : No , honey , not here . - Shh .
They 're sleeping .
Baby , come here , you 'll like it , believe me .
- Okay , let 's get down to business . - No , no , no .
Okay , just for a second , then .
Yeah .
- No , no , no . - Come on .
I have to . Wait , wait , wait .
Yeah .
[ MOANING ]
- Ow ! - Oh , sorry .
Oh , Jesus .
Jesus , honey . Damn it .
[ KNOCKING ]
Esther ?
We have to talk about last night .
- Do we ? - Yes , we do .
See , there are certain things that grown-ups do
that children aren 't supposed to see .
And that was one of them .
Esther , listen to me .
When grown-ups love each other very , very much
they wanna show each other that love . Express it .
I know . They fuck .
She could 've picked it up anywhere . Probably at school .
This wasn 't something she overheard . I mean , she knew what it meant .
Huh .
And , babe , the way she said it is- -
I don 't even think she expected to get in trouble over it .
Well , we 'll talk to her about it tonight .
Fine .
Well , what did you have in mind ?
No , I thought we could take her to Dr. Browning .
I don 't think we need to take her to the shrink quite yet .
Well , you know , we just don 't know that much about her .
The family she stayed with could 've been like :
" Pass the fucking potatoes " at dinnertime , you know ?
If she 's saying it to my face , what is she saying when we 're not there ?
I don 't want her exerting that kind of influence over Max .
Anyway , I just don 't want to make a big deal out of one little dirty word .
Fine . Fucking spend some time with her , then .
All right , bitch .
[ LAUGHS ]
[ KIDS CHATTERING AND LAUGHING ]
GIRL : Let 's have a snow fight !
WOMAN 1 : Come on , no throwing snowballs .
WOMAN 2 : Hey , neighbor .
- Hey . - Haven 't seen you around lately .
JOHN : I 've been pretty busy .
Has the homeowners ' association been soldiering on without me ?
It 's not the same .
[ BOTH CHUCKLE ]
Um , actually , I had a favor to ask .
I have a chair that I need moved upstairs
and I was hoping you could come by and help me with that sometime .
Yeah .
- Yeah , sure . - Good .
Maybe Kate and I could help you out . Just let us know .
I 'll call you .
Let 's go , honey .
MAN : Okay , I 'm watching you .
[ SCREAMING ]
[ CRYING ]
Brenda 's father says that you pushed her .
That 's not true .
We were just playing .
I swear .
- Okay . - And did you see what happened ?
[ SIGNING ]
What ? Mom , what 's she saying ?
She wants you to pass the bread and butter .
- Wasn 't asking you . JOHN : Hey , now .
Can you eat normal ?
I am eating normal .
Yeah , maybe in Transylvania , or whatever country you 're from .
Incidentally , I 'm from Russia .
Transylvania isn 't even a country . It 's a part of Romania .
You are such a freak .
- Hey . - Hey , Danny .
I don 't want any more talk like that .
But why does she have to act like that ?
All my friends make fun of me because of her .
Maybe you need different friends .
Maybe you should send her back to the retard camp .
- Daniel . - Daniel .
Apologize to your sister .
She 's not my fucking sister .
JOHN : I got it .
Okay .
That 's me .
You get the key back when you say you 're sorry .
Is there anything special you want me to make tonight ?
You have any favorites ?
[ CELL PHONE RINGING ]
Hello .
- Well , how are you ? - Hi , we 're great . We 're doing good .
- How is she ? KATE : She 's here , hold on .
Hey , Sister Abigail . Do you wanna say hello ?
- Come on . Esther , just quickly say hi . - I said , no .
You know what , do you mind , darling , can you get five apples for me ?
Sorry , she got shy all of a sudden .
It 's all right . I 'm just calling to remind you
that I 'm gonna need her medical
and dental charts for my supervision report .
She 's not thrilled about the dentist .
How is everyone doing ? Is she opening up to you ?
I guess you can say that . She dropped the F-bomb on me a few weeks ago .
[ SIGNING ]
I guess she 's finally coming out of her shell .
[ LAUGHS ]
Yeah .
Any other glitches I should know of ?
We had a big one recently .
It 's a girl named Brenda at school .
They were at the playground , there was a slide , well , she fell off .
Esther may have pushed her down .
I 'm not getting the story straight , but she got hurt .
Is she all right ?
Luckily . She broke her ankle and had something like six stitches .
That doesn 't sound too lucky .
Well , she 's lucky she didn 't break her neck .
[ PIANO PLAYING ]
You told me you didn 't know how to play .
- No , I didn 't . - Yes , you did .
You offered to teach me and I accepted .
Okay . So then you were just pretending this whole time ?
I thought you would enjoy teaching me .
It must be frustrating for someone who loves music as much as you
to have a son who isn 't interested and a daughter who can 't even hear .
Wait , wait , wait .
I walk in on her playing T chaikovsky without a mistake .
I mean , she 's been lying to me this whole time .
JOHN : She just wants to spend time with you . It 's hardly a lie .
KATE : You wouldn 't know .
You wouldn 't . She 's on her best behavior with you .
She 's completely different with me .
So , what are you saying ?
I don 't know . She threw a fit at school .
She pushed Brenda at the playground .
- Now you 're saying that was her fault ? - I don 't know . Honey , I don 't know .
I wasn 't there . You were watching them .
Oh , come on . It was an accident .
Okay , let 's not blame her for anything , fine .
I 'll take her word for everything .
Should I just believe what she said about you and Joyce too ?
What did she say ?
- She says that you were hitting on her . - What ?
Oh , come on . She must 've misunderstood . It was , like ... .
Did she invite you over ?
She asked me to help her move a chair .
- She did ? - Yeah . I blew her off .
Oh , God .
Why didn 't you tell me ?
- I-- - We could 've laughed about it .
- No , I knew how- - - You were hiding it .
Honey , I knew how you 'd react .
Kate . Kate .
You can 't get jealous of every woman that I talk to , right ?
- It 's been like 10 years . - What does that mean ?
You say that like it actually means something .
It 's only been two years since you told me .
You know how sorry I am . I just feel like I 've earned a little trust here .
- I gave you a second chance . - That 's not fair . That 's not fair .
Let me get this straight . We can talk about my mistakes , not yours ?
I was sick ! You were an asshole who wanted to fuck somebody else !
You put our child 's life in danger .
I could 've walked away months ago . Nobody would 've blamed me .
Oh , that 's sharp . That 's sharp . Where did you get that from , your mother ?
[ ROCK MUSIC PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS ]
Danny . Turn that crap down , please , I gotta work .
- Fine . - Thank you .
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]
ESTHER : I 'll get it .
- Hello , Esther . - What are you doing here ?
May I come in ?
I 'm afraid I may have made a mistake .
There could be something wrong with Esther .
What ?
What ? You told us that you 'd never had any trouble with her .
I didn 't . But trouble does have a way of finding her .
What kind of trouble ?
Two girls get into a fight , there she is .
Someone gets caught stealing , there she is again .
- So ? Does that mean- - ? - Just let her finish .
After you told me about the girl in the playground , I called her old school .
While she was there , there was a boy
who fell with scissors in his hand
and accidentally stabbed himself through the jaw .
And Esther was there again .
I don 't understand . He accidentally stabbed himself .
But the most troubling thing is the Sullivan house fire .
I checked into it further . It was arson .
They have never found the person who did it .
JOHN : What are you suggesting here ?
That she had anything to do with any of this ?
It 's ridiculous .
ABIGAIL : That a child could commit such crimes
it flies in the face of everything I believe .
Well , yeah .
[ DOOR OPENS ]
There 's a mean lady here . She 's come to take me away .
Will you help me ?
We 've had some behavioral problems , but ... .
Yeah , nothing like that . I mean , right ?
- Yes , we have . JOHN : Really , hon , think about it .
ABIGAIL : I 've tried to reach the Russian orphanage where she was raised .
I think we need to know what we 're dealing with .
Well , I 'll tell you what we 're dealing with .
KATE : No , you know what ? - Stop it . Listen .
We 're dealing with a 9-year-old girl who 's an orphan , okay ?
- We 're taking her to Dr. Browning . - We can take her to Dr. Browning .
[ SIGNING ]
[ SPEAKING ] Do you want to play ?
ABIGAIL : I 'll call you as soon as I find anything else out .
JOHN : Right . Take care . KATE : Okay . Thank you very much .
Maybe later .
It 's going to be fine .
We 'll scare her so bad she 'll never come back here .
Here she comes .
Wave your arms and make her stop .
Max , go .
[ YELLS ]
[ GROANING ]
You all right ? Max ?
Max ?
You okay ?
[ SCREAMING ]
Stop crying .
Grab a foot and help me get her off the road .
Now .
[ ABIGAIL GRUNTING ]
Help me hide her .
[ SIGNING ]
That doesn 't matter .
They 'll send you to jail just for helping me hide her .
I had to kill her because she was going to tell on me .
You 're not going to tell on me . Are you ?
Don 't worry .
You 're my little sister .
I won 't let anything happen to you .
I love you .
Tell me what you saw .
- What are you doing ? - What did you see ?
I saw you and Max in the tree house .
What else ?
- What do you mean ? - What else did you see ?
I didn 't see anything . I swear .
- Did you tell anyone ? - No .
I didn 't tell anyone .
Please ... .
If I find out that you 're lying , I 'll cut your hairless little prick off
before you even figure out what it 's for .
- Do you understand me ? - Yes .
You pissed yourself .
It was nice talking to you , Alice . I hope we can be friends .
I 'd like that .
- We 'll be right out , honey . - You can come on in .
My initial instinct is that
there 's not a deeply-rooted problem in Esther 's past .
- So there 's nothing wrong with her ? - No .
It 's not all good news . I think what needs to be examined
is Esther 's relationship with those around her .
Specifically with you , Kate .
It seems she feels there 's been some real tension between the two of you .
- Okay . - She 's doing her best to please you
but you 're blocking her attempts to bond .
That 's not true . That 's not true at all . I 've done everything .
- Right ? - Just let her finish .
Something 's happening to cause Esther to feel this way .
Perhaps it 's your guilt about drinking or what happened to Max .
Maybe some of your feelings of inadequacy as a mother
are manifesting themselves in your relationship with Esther .
I don 't feel inadequate .
What did she tell you ?
She didn 't see . She doesn 't know .
She 's so stupid .
Esther 's a very shy , reserved
sensitive little girl going through an extremely difficult time .
[ GRUNTING ]
She 's exceptionally bright and highly articulate .
She just needs a little patience and understanding .
[ SCREAMS ]
Thanks for your support back there .
That was your idea .
[ CELL PHONE RINGING ]
Kate , wait , wait , wait .
I 'm not a psychiatrist , but a lot of what she said made sense .
Do you wanna get that ?
- Hello ? WOMAN : Hello , is this Mrs. Coleman ?
Yes . Who 's this ?
This is Sister Judith from St. Mariana 's .
I 'm sorry to bother you , but I need to know
if Sister Abigail made it to her appointment with you .
Yes . Why ?
She hasn 't returned since yesterday
and I 'm just starting to get really worried .
MAN : Charlie 24 , you wanna hold them there ?
Hey .
MAN : Okay , I think we 're done .
KATE : Detective , do you have any leads or suspects ?
MAN : No , not yet . - I just don 't understand
this kind of thing . Who would do this ? It 's ... .
Awful .
You think of anything else , you give us a call .
KATE : Yes . Absolutely .
Let 's go .
This is what Sister Abigail was talking about . Look .
" Character-disturbed children . " Look at the symptoms .
" Superficially charming . Difficulty at making and keeping friends . "
I 'm not sure this is what she meant .
She could 've told Dr. Browning whatever she wanted to hear . Look .
They " are adroit manipulators
oftentimes playing people off one another to get what they want . "
Well , you gonna show this to Dr. Browning ?
I 'm not showing her anything .
I 'm not seeing her anymore .
- When did you decide that ? - When do you think ?
You 're gonna discount Dr. Browning ?
Why does everyone get the benefit of the doubt from you except for me ?
If you need help with the kids , we can arrange that .
I don 't need help .
I just wanna know more about her .
I wanna know where she came from , and I wanna know who she is .
What if Sister Abigail was right ?
I mean , if someone was in danger , our own children ...
- ... wouldn 't you wanna know ? - Of course I would .
I 'll contact the orphanage she came from in Russia . All right ?
I mean , it 's a start .
[ CLATTERING ]
- What ? JOHN : Hey .
Fine .
I was wondering if you 'd heard from anyone at the Sludyanka Shelter .
Sister Abigail had mentioned that she would- -
Oh , you did .
I don 't understand . How can they have no record of her being there ?
Yes , please .
Could you just call me as soon as you know anything , please ? Thank you .
JOHN : Esther , we gotta go .
Esther ?
You got me .
[ JOHN LAUGHS ]
- What ? - I don 't want to go to the dentist .
- Why not ? - I just don 't want to go .
- What , are you scared ? - No .
We 're gonna reschedule , though .
Tell you what , I 'll let you play hooky if you want to come and draw with me .
All right .
KATE : Wait , Daniel .
How are you two getting along with Esther ?
Fine , I guess .
KATE : Yeah ? DANIEL : Yeah , Mom .
But has she ever made you feel , I don 't know , uncomfortable
or has she done anything that she 's not supposed to do ?
- No . - Like , has she ever hurt any of you ?
DANIEL : No .
You sure ?
Okay . All right .
ESTHER : I like it when it 's just the two of us .
You don 't know how long I 've waited for a daddy just like you .
Mommy too , right ?
I don 't think Mommy likes me very much .
Hey .
- That is not true . Mommy loves you . - It 's all right .
It must be hard to love an adopted child as much as your own .
Sweetheart , you 're just as much a part of this family as Danny and Max . Okay ?
Do something nice for Mommy . Show her how much you love her .
That 's a wonderful idea .
I have a special surprise for you , Mommy .
You do ?
I picked these flowers just for you .
- Esther , what did you do ? God . ESTHER : My arm !
KATE : Why did you do this ? - Daddy , my arm !
[ ESTHER SCREAMS ]
KATE : John ! - Hey .
KATE : What did you do ? JOHN : Hey . Stop , stop .
Why did you do this ?
- Oh , God . God , she did this on purpose . - No , no , no .
- Yes , she did . - Hey . Honey , no .
She knew what these roses meant to me .
It 's my fault , hon . I told her to do something nice for you .
I can 't believe this .
[ GROANING ]
[ MUFFLED SCREAMING ]
ESTHER : Daddy !
Daddy !
Daddy , Daddy !
What is it , honey ?
My arm still hurts .
Can I have a look at it ? You 're okay .
I 'll be gentle . It 's all right , honey .
Oh , my God .
We need to take you to the hospital .
JOHN : You 're a brave little girl , you know that ?
Doctor said you 're gonna heal real fast , okay ?
You broke her arm .
KATE : It 's impossible . I didn 't grab her that hard .
She wants to sleep in here tonight . Maybe you should sleep downstairs .
I 'm having guests for dinner .
You know , you can have it . Thanks .
KATE : Have a good day .
Daniel .
Your books .
- What happened ? Let me see your bag . - I don 't know .
We just bought this . Pick it up , it 's gonna get wet .
Mom !
KATE : Max ! No ! Help !
Max !
[ KATE SCREAMING ]
[ CAR HORN HONKING ]
Max !
Are you okay ?
I 'm here . Mommy 's here . You 're okay , honey . Come on .
I got you . Yeah . Oh , baby , it 's okay . I 'm so sorry .
I remember I put it in park and I set the brake .
Max didn 't indicate that Esther did anything .
Well , Max is covering for her . And I don 't think it 's the first time .
It also wouldn 't be the first time you blamed Esther for your own mistake .
You know what ? I want her out of this house .
You 're ready for somebody to come and take her ?
I am . I don 't care .
I will do whatever it takes to protect my children .
The girls found this this morning .
The girls found it . You mean Esther found it .
Yes , Esther . Does it make any difference ? Is she lying ?
BROWNING : You need help .
We 've reserved a place for you in a rehabilitation facility
about 45 minutes from here .
KATE : I didn 't drink it .
I bought two bottles . I poured one of them down the sink .
- But not this one ? - No .
John , I haven 't had a drink in almost a year .
We wanna help you , but there 's nothing we can do ...
- ... until you stop lying to yourself . KATE : I 'm not lying . I wanted to drink it .
You have no fucking idea how badly I wanted to drink it , but I didn 't .
- I didn 't drink it . - If Max had gotten hurt ... .
What happened this morning has nothing to do with this .
I find that hard to believe .
The only reason that I 'm sober is because of Max and Daniel .
I think about what would have happened had you not been there
and it makes me wanna kill myself .
I would never do anything
to let something like that ever happen again . I wouldn 't .
That is so manipulative .
I know I haven 't given you reason to believe me , I know I haven 't .
I lied to you . I should have told you about this .
I 'll go to therapy , I 'll go to fucking A.A. if that 's what you want ...
- ... but you have to believe me . - I don 't .
You have to believe me . John , you have to trust me on this .
I 'll give you a week to go to rehab
or I 'm leaving and I 'm taking the kids with me .
I think that 's fair , okay ?
I 'll help you as much as I can , make it really easy .
Mom 's gonna come in the afternoon .
All right ? I 'm willing to do this . I 'm willing to try and figure this out .
- But it 's up to you . - I 'll shoot Mommy if you tell .
[ ESTHER HUMMING ]
Max . Max , are you okay ?
What did she do ? Did she do something to make the car crash ?
If you saw her , you have to help me , so Mom and Dad can protect us .
[ SIGNING ]
Why not ?
Is that Sister Abigail ?
Max . What did she do in my tree house ?
Are the bad things still there ?
Everything 's gonna be okay .
I 'll get the stuff from the tree house . Then they 'll have to believe us .
- Going somewhere , Kate ? - What are you doing here ?
She 's fine . Let 's not wake her .
Go to your room .
Honestly , we 're past that now . Aren 't we ?
I know what you 're doing .
I will not let you hurt my children .
Me ?
I 'm not the one who passed out drunk and let Max almost drown in the pond .
If it wasn 't for John
she 'd be dead , and you 'd probably still be in jail .
Who told you that ?
It 's very intimate .
- I learned so much . - Give it to me .
- Jessica . Your cheating husband . - Esther , give it to me .
Where you hide your wine bottles .
I 'm- - I 'm warning you right now .
" She was still kicking when the doctor told me
it was something called phantom
fetal movement .
- For 16 days , I carried my dead baby . " - Stop it . Esther .
" It was the cruelest torture I could imagine . "
Stop it . You stop it .
What 's wrong with you ?
Kate , it 's too late . It 's your own fault .
You took your family for granted .
- What do you mean ? - What are you going to do ?
Hit me ?
We adopted her from you . How could you not know anything ?
The Sullivans could have adopted her illegally .
She doesn 't remember anything that could help us ?
I 'm gonna call you back .
" Saarne Institute . "
[ LINE RINGING ]
[ WOMAN SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE OVER PHONE ]
Hello . Do you speak English ?
[ WOMAN SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
Do you speak English ?
Is there anyone who speaks English there ?
This is very important .
[ SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
I don 't know what you 're saying .
- Hello ? - Is this the Saarne Institute ?
Yes .
Yes . I need to talk to somebody about one of your children .
She was adopted by an American family . It 's a girl .
She is not come from here .
Well , I haven 't even told you her name yet .
You do not understand . Saarne Institute is not an orphanage .
It is a mental hospital .
Are you looking for this ?
Poor Sister Abigail .
I couldn 't have done it myself , you know . Max is just as guilty as I am .
- Whatever Max did , you made her do it . - Think about it .
How did she even know what was up here ?
It 's always better to burn the evidence .
If they find these things , they won 't just be coming for me .
They 'll be coming for Max too .
- Is that really what you want ? - Wait .
What are you doing ?
Are you crazy ?
Let me out !
Let me out of here !
Mom !
It 's called the Saarne Institute . S-A-A-R-N-E , Saarne .
It 's in Estonia .
Estonia ? No , this can 't be right . All of her paperwork is from Russia .
I 'm sending them a picture of her right now .
Maybe her birth mother was a patient there .
I don 't know . Maybe she was even born there .
Mom !
Help !
[ SCREAMING AND GRUNTING ]
Mom ! Dad !
Oh , God !
[ SCREAMS ]
Oh , God . Call 911 !
Don 't worry . You 're going to heaven .
KATE : Oh , God !
Oh , my God ! Daniel !
Move away ! Move away from the fire !
Daniel ?
Oh , God , no . Daniel ? Mommy 's right here . Can you hear me ?
Please wake up . Honey , Mommy 's right here , okay ?
You 're gonna be all right .
We stopped the abdominal bleeding , but he has a very serious neck injury .
He 's stabilized for now . You should consider yourselves very lucky .
- Can we see him ? DOCTOR : In a little while .
He 's resting in the ICU .
Okay . And will he be able to tell us what happened ?
DOCTOR : It 's possible .
No way of knowing for sure what he 'll remember until he wakes up .
Excuse me .
It 's gonna be okay .
JOHN : I know you 're exhausted and upset , and so am I .
There has to be some other explanation . She didn 't come from an insane asylum .
The orphanage you thought she came from has never heard of her .
Everything about her could be a lie .
We have her passport . We have school records , medical records .
These are papers from around the world .
What is this ? It 's a piece of paper .
Your own mother was there this time . It wasn 't just me . Your mother was there .
It 's either Esther or Daniel who started the fire .
- Who do you think it was ? - I don 't know .
I 'm so done . I 'm done connecting these dots for you .
You know , you can think whatever you want about me .
I will leave tonight . If that 's what you want , I will leave tonight .
On one condition . Esther goes too .
Can I have a dollar for the soda machine ?
Your mother wants you to stay right there .
There you go . Don 't be too long .
[ SIGNING ]
Okay .
[ DANIEL GROANING ]
What ? What is it , sweetie ?
MAN [ OVER SPEAKER ] : Code 99 , ICU .
Code 99 , ICU .
MAN : Coming through , coming through . - Mom , take Max .
WOMAN : Let 's go , Room 304 ! Crash cart coming through ! Move , people !
KATE : Daniel ? MAN : Clear the hall ! Clear the hall !
You have to stay out here . He 's in cardiac arrest . Stay out here .
Daniel !
WOMAN : Here we go . MAN : Start a drip .
WOMAN : Check BP , please . MAN : Check ventilation .
Oh , God .
MAN : We got a pulse . We got a pulse .
Kate .
What did you do ? What did you do to him , you bitch ?
JOHN : Stop , stop !
WOMAN : Orderlies ! KATE : She 's trying to kill my baby !
- Daddy ! - Hold her !
KATE : She 's trying to kill my baby !
Hold her still .
KATE : Get off me .
Hold her still . Hold her still .
Okay . Easy , easy .
- You okay ? - There you go .
[ PHONE RINGING ]
- Kate . - Daniel .
They 're running tests . We should know more tomorrow .
Don 't worry about Daniel . He 'll be okay .
He 'll be home in a few days .
You need to stay here , get some rest .
I 'm gonna take Max and Esther home .
Johnny .
Please don 't let her near Max .
I love you .
[ BEEPING ]
[ MUTED SOUND ]
[ SIGNING ]
ESTHER : Hello , Daddy .
- What are you wearing ? - Do you like it ?
Oh , Jesus .
Look at you . What have you done to your face ? What is this ?
I don 't want to be alone . I 'm scared .
I love you , Daddy .
You too , hon .
I really love you .
I know .
John , let me take care of you .
What are you doing ? What are you doing ?
What 's gotten into you , huh ? What 's going on ?
You said you loved me .
You are so confused .
You know what ? I don 't love you like that .
That 's the way Kate and I love each other .
You understand ?
I don 't see that .
- You have to respect your mother . - I do .
I just feel like I 'm alone sometimes in respecting you .
I don 't think anyone ever thinks about what you might be feeling .
I really care about you , John .
Yeah , I know , Esther .
I 'm just- - I 'm tired .
I 'm very tired .
And I don 't know what to do . It 's difficult .
I mean , everything is just falling apart
and , oh , my God , I 'm so worried for Daniel .
Oh , God .
You 're a good person , John .
You 're a great father .
And a handsome man .
Jesus Christ !
My God , stop , stop , stop !
Just stop talking and go upstairs ! Go to your room !
- Stop talking to me like I 'm a child . - I 'm calling Sister Judith tomorrow .
We 're gonna have a conversation about your future in this house .
I just- - I can 't do it anymore .
ESTHER : Fine .
Esther .
[ PHONE RINGING ]
- Hello ? MAN : Is this Katherine Coleman ?
- Hello ? - Yeah . This is she .
My name is Dr. Värava . I 'm calling from the Saarne Institute .
- I 've just seen the picture you e-mailed . - And do you recognize her ?
Where is she right now ? Is she someplace where she can hear you ?
No , she 's not with me . She 's with my husband at home .
Call your husband right now , and tell him to get your family out of the house .
- And then call the police . - He won 't listen to me . But why ?
Then tell him the little girl in the picture is not really a little girl .
- She 's a grown woman . - What ?
What are you talking about ? The picture I sent you
is of our adopted daughter , and she 's 9 years old .
No , she 's not .
She has a rare hormone disorder . It 's called hypopituitarism .
It causes proportional dwarfism . She only looks like a child .
According to our records , Leena Klammer was born in 1976 .
She 's 33 years old .
This can 't be . This is a mistake .
I hope so , for your sake . Does she have the scars ?
What ? I don 't know . What scars ?
Leena was one of our most violent patients .
When she was here , she was kept in a straitjacket
to stop her from hurting our staff .
She was constantly fighting to get out .
It cut into her skin and left her with scars around her wrists and neck .
There is no way you could not have seen them .
Why was she at your hospital ?
She 's dangerously ill , violent . She killed seven people that we know of .
Oh , my God . How could she fool us ?
She has been passing herself off as a little girl for most of her life .
She tricked a family here in Estonia into adopting her .
When she couldn 't seduce the father , she killed him and his whole family .
- Then she burned the house down . - Yes . How did you know ?
She disappeared a year ago and we lost track of her .
If it 's really Leena , you don 't have much time .
[ SCREAMING ]
Esther ?
[ PHONE RINGING ]
[ LINE RINGING ]
Come on , Johnny . Come on . Pick up the fucking phone .
Shit .
Come on .
[ TRUCK HORN HONKING ]
Oh , God !
[ SCREAMS ]
Come on .
[ LINE RINGING ]
WOMAN [ OVER PHONE ] : 911 . What is your emergency ?
I need the police . We have an intruder in our home .
[ THUDS ]
[ JOHN GROANING ]
[ PHONE RINGING ]
Come on .
JOHN [ ON RECORDING ] : This is John . - John ?
You 've reached my cell , but I can 't pick up .
Oh , fuck it .
[ GRUNTING ]
John ?
John ? John ?
No , God !
Max .
[ CLATTERING ]
[ GUNSHOT ]
What the fuck ?
[ SIGNING ]
Esther ! Don 't you hurt her !
Leave her alone ! I 'm here !
Esther !
[ SIREN WAILING ]
I know .
[ KATE GASPS ]
Go back . It 's too dangerous . Go back .
Please .
Don 't let me die , Mommy .
I 'm not your fucking Mommy !
Baby , it 's okay .
[ ENGLISH SDH ]